

VARSHA KAKWANI

VARSHAKAKWANI@GMAIL.COM +919958482861

SUMMARY

Compassionate, creative and effective teacher with valuable experience in classroom administration, professional development and lesson planning. Equipped with extensive background in versatile education environments. Competent at performing independently or as member of teaching team. Wellversed in classroom and online technologies.

SKILLS

- Student engagement
- Experiential learning
- Student-Centered Learning
- Classroom management
- Technological Instruction
- Positive Reinforcement
- Curriculum Development
- Lesson Planning
- Leadership

EXPERIENCE

PRT ENGLISH • THE MAURYA SCHOOL, GURUGRAM, HARYANA

JULY 2019 TO MARCH 2020

 Evaluated and revised lesson plans and course content to facilitate and moderate classroom discussions and student-centered learning.

CLASS COORDINATOR (GRADE 3) • THE MODERN SCHOOL, HARYANA APRIL 2018 TO MARCH 2019

- Established positive, stimulating learning environment for students and exciting education-focused setting for teachers.
- Helped fellow teachers with day-to-day work and complex problems by applying motivational and analytical strategies.

PRT ENGLISH • THE MODERN SCHOOL, HARYANA

MARCH 2016 TO MARCH 2019

 Designed comprehensive English and EVS workbooks for students of Grade 1, 2 and 3.

PRT ENGLISH • RICHMONDD GLOBAL SCHOOL, NEW DELHI MARCH 2015 TO MARCH 2016

MAROII 2013 TO MAROII 2010

PRT ENGLISH • MOTHER DIVINE PUBLIC SCHOOL, NEW DELHI OCTOBER 2014 TO MARCH 2015

EDUCATION

- BACHELOR OF EDUCATION 2014 UNIVERSITY OF JAMMU
- BACHELOR OF ARTS (ENGLISH) 2013 UNIVERSITY OF DELHI
- MASTERS OF ARTS (ENGLISH) PURSUING UNIVERSITY OF DELHI

INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE

INTERN • BEQURIO, GURUGRAM

NOVEMBER 2014 TO FEBRUARY 2015

ENGLISH PROJECT FELLOW • MAKE A DIFFERENCE (NGO), NEW DELHI APRIL 2013 TO MARCH 2014

- Handled day-to-day running of The English Project, ensuring high levels of productivity and progression.
- Managed team of volunteers, overseeing hiring and training.
- Identified issues, analyzed information and provided solutions to the problems for smooth flow of the project.

ENGLISH PROJECT MENTOR AND TEACHER • MAKE A DIFFERENCE (NGO), NEW DELHI

SEPTEMBER 2012 TO APRIL 2013